Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Hockey
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting hockey
1895-1998
RU 938
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
17.75
(15 boxes)
The records consist of scrapbooks, correspondence, manager"s files, and publications maintained by the Yale University Department of Athletics documenting hockey at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005 and 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Existence and Location of Copies
Hockey scrapbooks for the years 1919-1941 are available on microfilm from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM182. 1984. 1750 frames on 2 reels, 35mm.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of scrapbooks, correspondence, manager"s files, and publications maintained by the Yale University Department of Athletics documenting hockey at Yale.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
College sports; Hockey; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Hockey; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Scrapbooks of the ice hockey team, 1919-1960; Accession 2006-A-038
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Patrons must use HM FILM 182 instead of the original scrapbooks for the years 1919-1941.
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1919-1920 (Box 1, Reel 1U)
    - 1921-1922 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
    - 1922-1924 (Box 3, Reel 1U)
    - 1924-1926 (Box 4, Reel 1U)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 5, Reel 2U)
    - 1935-1941 (Box 6, Reel 2U)
    - 1942-1956 (not microfilmed) (Box 8)
    - 1956-1960 (not microfilmed) (Box 7)
- Manager's files of the ice hockey team, 1934-1950; Accession 2006-A-049
  - Freshmen, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Varsity and freshmen (combined), 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
- Men's and women's ice hockey records, 1895-2005; Accession 2006-A-250
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2029
  - Men
    - Historical Background, 1895-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General
    - 1933-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Scorecards (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1963-64
      - 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Varsity, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Frosh, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Varsity, 1966-67 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Frosh, 1966-67 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General
      - 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ingalls Rink Renovation, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 14)
    - "Salute", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ingalls Rink Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Hockey Association - C. Pagnam, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - General, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Photographs, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Newsletters, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Clippings, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - General, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Hockey Association, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - General
      - 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25 - 26)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ECAC, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - General
      - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Game Summary Sheets
      - 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 33 - 35)
      - 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 36 - 37)
    - Hockey Association, 1993-94 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - General, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Yearly Log, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 40 - 42)
    - Media Questionnaire, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Lineup cards
      - Varsity, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
      - Freshmen, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Women
    - General
      - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 51 - 52)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Publications
    - Men
      - 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - 1970-1980 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - No date (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Women
      - 1976-2005 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Scrapbook and photographs of Murray Murdoch, 1918-1937; Accession 2017-A-028
  Biographical / Historical
  The scrapbook contains photographs and news clippings related to the NHL career of Murray Murdoch, who played left wing for the New York Rangers in 508 games with 84 goals and 108 assists from the Rangers' first season in the 1926–27 NHL season until the 1936–37 NHL season. From 1938 to 1965, he was the sixth head coach of Yale University hockey team. In 1974, he was awarded the Lester Patrick Trophy for his contribution to hockey in the United States.
  - Team photograph of St. John's College senior hockey team (Murdoch is top left), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Team photograph of St. John's College school rugby team (Murdoch is bottom center), 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook of Murray Murdoch, 1926-1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)